Kasey Powers

Indianapolis, Indiana, United States

kaseyepowers@gmail.com

(317) 460-7953

linkedin.com/in/kaseypowers

https://github.com/KaseyPowers

Summary

Software Engineer with 8 years experience focused on Front-End Web Development, with a focus on working with UX Designers goals and delivering high quality results.

Trained in using Typescript or Javascript along with frameworks such as React and AngularJS, and CSS style libraries featuring Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, and Material UI.

Led the development of multiple applications and widgets, while striving to help mentor and aid other developers.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Prime Trust

Apr 2019 - Nov 2023 (4 years 8 months)

- Tech lead of a team of full-stack engineers for project migrating key internal front-end tools used by 75+ in sales, compliance and finance operation from Ember to React JSX with GraphQL and Ant Design frameworks.
- Complied with requirements of financial regulations.
- Built suites of tools to improve developer experience, including hooks, contexts, wrapping react-router to build navigation UI, and GraphQL tools that automatically apply filters from pagination and generating filter options from the schema.
- Built and maintained 10+ apps and embedded scripts integrated into customer applications, including a credit-card processing app that handled over 2 Million transactions.
- Improved security and PCI compliance of credit card and other private data collection while refactoring to isolate relevant codebases without interrupting the users experience.
- Maintained a reputation as a helpful resource across the company for questions around the front-end as well as mentored 5 full-stack developers starting from a range of experience from recent bootcamp grads to senior level by teaching Javascript, ES6 and React concepts until they were comfortable doing feature work unassisted.

♦ Developer 1A

Availity

May 2015 - Mar 2019 (3 years 11 months)

- Worked in a regulated environment, complying with HIPAA and government accessibility requirements.
- Rebuilt the home page and navigation, with new frameworks (angularJS) and styling, serving 50k unique visitors per month.
- Continuous contributions to companies' open source tools and libraries.
- Reworked internal angular services to be usable with other frameworks like React (github.com/Availity/sdk-js). While doing so, cleaned up code with new ES6 syntax and updated tests using Jest.
- Responsible for the mentorship and training of team members new to front-end development.
- Provided assistance to employees across teams with AngularJS as well as internal tools and libraries.

Education



Florida Institute of Technology

BS, Software Engineering 2011 - 2015

Skills

React.js • Node.js • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Web Development • Tailwind CSS • HTML • JavaScript • TypeScript